She's having my baby, and she's not here yet.
她将生下我的小孩,她却还没来
-Has her water broken yet? -I don't know.
-她的羊水破了吗? -我不知道
When we talked,she said she'd already passed the mucous plug.
她和我通话时说她已分泌粘液
Do we have to know about that?
我们需要知道这一些吗?
What'll you do when you have a baby?
乔伊,你有小孩时你会怎么做?
I'll be in the waiting room, handing out cigars.
我会在等待室中送雪茄
Joey's made arrangements to have his baby in a movie from the '50s.
乔伊准备让他孩子出生在50年代的电影中
She could be giving birth in the cab.
我不敢相信她可能会在计程车中生产
Relax. It's only $2 for the first contraction...
罗斯,冷静点第一次收缩收费二块钱
...and then 50 cents for each additional contraction.
之后每收缩一次收五毛钱
What,it's okay when Chandler does it?
什么?钱德这样说时就没事
You have to pick your moments.
你得选对时间
Did I miss it?
我错过了吗?
-She's not here yet. -What's with the guitar?
-没有,她根本还没出现 -干嘛带吉他来?
We might be here for a while. Things might get musical.
我想我们会在这儿待一阵子,来点音乐
-Where have you been? -We stopped at the gift shop.
-你到底上哪儿去了? -我们中途在礼品店待了一会儿
I got this, and Susan wanted a Chunky.
我想买这个,苏珊想买“矮胖”
You're having a baby. You don't stop for Chunkies.
你就快生小宝宝了. 是小宝宝不能中途下车买矮胖
I used to have that bumper sticker.
我过去也用那个汽车贴纸
You see what I mean?
懂我意思吗?
The One With the Birth
六人行 第1季 第23集 本出世
-=BT之家DRM小组 http://bbs.btbbt.com=- 荣誉出品 河马根据网络字幕微调制作
-"Stopped for a Chunky." -Let it go,Ross.
-下车买矮胖 -别介意了,罗斯
I got an extra one. You want this?
我多了一个,想要吗?不想
-How's my favorite parenting team? -Dr. Franzblau.
-我最喜爱的父母团队好 -法大夫
I understand you're thinking of having a baby.
我了解你们在考虑生宝宝的事
I see you're nine months pregnant. That's a good start.
我知道你已怀胎九月 这是好的开始
-How are your contractions? -I love them.
-收缩的情况如何? -我喜欢
Each one's like a little party in my uterus.
每一阵都像是子宫中的小舞会
-Every 4 minutes,lasting 55 seconds. -59 seconds. Quartz.
-每4分钟,持续55秒 -59秒,石英表
Swiss quartz.
瑞士石英表
-Am I allowed to drink anything? -lce chips.
-我能喝饮料吗? -碎冰
-At the nurse's station. -I'll get it!
-护士站有 -我去拿
-No,I'll get it. -No,I'm getting it.
-不,我去,马上回来 -不,我去…
Hi. Thought you might like some ice chips.
我想你或许想喝碎冰谢谢
-Thanks. -And if you need anything else l...
-谢谢. -如果还需要别的…
...do not believe we've met.
我没见过吧?
I'm Rachel Greene.
我叫瑞秋格林
I'm Carol's ex-husband's sister's roommate.
卡萝前任丈夫妹抹的室友
Nice to meet you. I'm Dr. Franzblau.
幸会,我是法大夫
I'm your roommate's brother's ex-wife's obstetrician.
你室友哥哥前妻的医生
Oh,that's funny.
真有趣
I want a baby.
我要个宝宝
Not tonight,honey. I got an early day tomorrow.
今晚不行,亲爱的我明天得早起
-Get up. Let's get some coffee. -Okay,because we never do that.
-起来,我们去买咖啡 -好吧,因为我们没做过
Shoot,shoot,shoot. Or just fall down. That's good too.
投.投.投.或是不进也行
Knick fan?
尼克斯迷?
-Oh,boy,do they suck. -Listen,lady
-他们烂透了 -听着,女士
Look. Look at your man,Ewing.
看,你的尤恩
He couldn't hit water if he was standing on a boat.
他连坐在船上都投不进水里
-And who do you like? -Celtics.
-是吗?你支持谁? -凯尔特人
Celtics? They couldn't hit a boat if
凯尔特人?他们不可能击中船队的如果
Wait....
等等
They suck,all right?
反正他们很烂
Shut up. It's a rebuilding year
闭嘴,今年是重建年
Let me get the father. We need a father over here.
我帮你叫孩子的爹,我们这儿需要爸爸…
There's no father.
这里没有爸爸
-Oh,sorry. -That's okay. I'm fine.
-抱歉 -没关系,我没事
Okay. Right this way.
这边来
All the other pregnant women seem to be going in here.
所有的孕妇似乎都往这儿走
They're tiny and chubby And so sweet to touch
他们又小又肉摸起来感觉很好
But soon they'll grow up And resent you so much
不久他们长大后就会开始恨你
Now they're yelling at you And you don 't know why
现在他们对你大吼大叫,你不知原因为何
And you cry and you cry And you cry
你只能哭啊,哭啊,你哭啊
-Thanks,Ross. -I'm paying you to stop.
-谢谢,罗斯 -用来叫你停止的好吧
Oh,look,twins. Hi,guys. Oh,cute.
看,是双胞胎,好可爱
No fair.
不公平
I don't even have one. How come they get two?
我一个都没有,他们怎会有两个?
-You'll get one. -When?
-你也会有的 -什么时候?
Tell you what. When we're 40, if neither of us are married...
好吧,告诉你.我们40岁时如果都还单身
...what do you say we have one?
我们就一起生一个,如何?
Why won't I be married when I'm 40?
为何我40岁时还单身?
I just meant hypothetically.
不,这只是假设
Hypothetically,why won't I be married when I'm 40?
假设为何我到40岁时还单身?
What is it? Is there something unmarriable about me?
为什么?我有不适婚姻的毛病吗?
Well?
好吧?
Dear God! This parachute is a knapsack.
亲爱的上帝!这降落伞是个背包
Look at you,dressy-dress.
看你,盛装登场
Did you go home and change?
你回家换衣服?
It's an important day. I want to look nice.
今天是个重要的日子,我想漂亮一点
Has Dr. Franzblau been by?
法大夫来了吗?
I haven't seen him.
不,我们还没见到他
Where is he? He is supposed to be here.
他在哪儿?他应该在这儿的
What if the baby needs him?
万一小孩需要他怎么办?
What's the deal with you and doctors? Is your father a doctor?
瑞秋,你和医生到底是怎么了 难道你爸也是个医生?
Yeah. Why?
对,干嘛问?
No reason.
没理由
Mom,we've been through this.
妈妈,我们能过这个
No,I am not calling him.
不,我不找他
I don't care if it is his kid, the guy's a jerk.
我不管这是不是他的孩子,他是个大浑蛋
No,I am not alone. Joey's here.
不,我不是一个人,乔伊在这儿
What do you mean "Joey who"?
什么意思?乔伊什么?
Joey who?
乔伊什么?
-Tribbiani. -Joey Tribbiani.
-崔比欧尼 -乔伊崔比欧尼
Yes. Okay. Hold on.
对,等等
She wants to talk to you.
她要跟你谈
Take the phone.
拿着电话
Yeah,it's me.
对,是我
No,we're just friends.
不,我们只是朋友
Yeah,I'm single.
对,我单身
Twenty-five.
25岁
An actor. Hello?
演员
She's not much of a phone person.
她不善于讲电话
So,what's the deal with this father guy?
孩子的爸怎么了?
If someone was having my baby, I'd wanna know about it.
如果有人即将生下我的孩子,我会想知道的
Hey,Knick fan,am I interested in your views on fatherhood? No.
尼克斯迷,你对爸爸的观点我不在乎
-Maybe I should just go. -Maybe you should.
-或许吧我应该走了. -也许应该
Good luck...
祝你好运
...and take care.
保重了
The Celtics problem is that the players run the team.
你知道凯尔特人有什么问题? 他们让球员经营球队这不是真的
-That is so not true. -Oh,it is.
-这不是真的 -这当然是真的
-Breathe. -Breathe.
-深呼吸 -深呼吸
You're gonna kill me.
你们会害死我的
-Fifteen more seconds. 1 4,1 3,1 2 -Count faster.
-剩15秒 -14,13,12数快点
It'll be okay. IKeep focusing on Jordy. He'll be here soon.
你会没事,记得这样做全是为了裘帝,他马上就到了
-Three. Two. Who the hell is Jordy? -Your son.
-3,2,1.裘帝到底是谁? -你儿子
I don't have a son named Jordy. We all agreed on Jamie.
不,我不要我儿子叫裘帝, 我们协议过,我儿子叫洁米
Jamie was the name of Susan's first girlfriend...
洁米是苏珊第一任女友的名字
...so we went back to Jordy.
所以我们决定还是用裘帝
What do you mean,back to Jordy? We never landed on Jordy.
这是什么意思?还是用裘帝, 我们根本没讨论过裘帝
We just passed by it during the whole Jesse-Cody-Dillon fiasco.
我们讨论过杰西科德迪伦时提到一下
Ow! Leg cramp!
我脚抽筋
-I got it. -I got it. I'm doing it.
-我明白了 -明白,我来处理
You get to sleep with her. I get the cramps.
你和她睡觉,我来处理抽筋
No,you don't.
你不行
That is it. I want both of you out.
够了,你们都给我出去
-She started it. -He did.
-什么?是她引起的… -他…
I'm trying to get a person out of my body here...
我不管,我想生下小孩
...and you're not making it any easier! Now go!
你们在这儿根本是愈帮愈忙
-Thanks. -See what you did?
-谢谢 -看你干了什么?
-Listen -Out!
-听着 -出去!
Breathe. Breathe.
深呼吸.深呼吸
What is that? Something exploded.
怎么了?有东西爆炸了
-That's not the baby,is it? -Her water broke. Calm down.
-不是婴儿 -她的羊水破了,冷静点
Water breaking? What do you mean? What's that?
羊水破了?你什么意思?
Breathe. Breathe.
深呼吸.深呼吸
I'm okay. I'm okay. That's disgusting. I'm okay.
我很好,我很好,这样真讨厌,我很好
-This is so your fault. -How is this my fault?
-这都是你的错 -为什么都是我的错?
Carol never threw me out of a room before you.
你们在一起之前卡萝从未把我赶出房间
There's a lot of things Carol never did before me.
我出现之前有许多事卡萝没做过
-Are you trying to be clever? -You're so threatened by me.
-知道你的问题出在哪儿吗? -你因我而感到岌岌可危
Hey. Okay,all right. That's it. Get in here.
嘿,ok,好吧,就这样,进去
My God,you guys. I don't believe you.
天哪,伙计们,我简直不敢相信你们两个
There are children coming into the world here...
小宝宝即将诞生在这栋建筑
...and your fighting isn't the first thing they should hear.
他听见的第一个声音不该是你们的吵闹声
So stop all the yelling! Just stop it!
所以你们别再吵了
Don't make me do this again! I don't like my voice like this!
对,苏珊,别让我再发一次脾气 我不喜欢我自己这样
Who wants to hear something ironic?
谁想听反讽的事?
Are they here yet?
他们到了吗?
Don't worry, we're gonna find them.
不要担心,我们会找到他们那的
And until we do, we are all here for you. Okay?
找到人之前,我们都会在这儿陪你的
You were telling me about Paris. It sounds wonderful.
你告诉我巴黎的事真棒
There was this great little pastry shop right by my hotel
那家糕饼店就在我住的饭店隔壁
There you go,dear.
加油,加油,亲爱的
-You find them? -Not in the gift shop or cafeteria....
-你找到他们啦? -不是在礼品店或者咖啡厅
Where are Phoebe and Joey?
菲比和乔伊在哪里?
There's something sinister going on here.
我想这里有点险恶
If you find anyone, or parts of anyone...
如果你找到任何人,或者任何人的一部分
...scream. And scream again.
就大叫,不停的大叫
-Help! -Come on!
-救命! -拜托
-I'm having a baby in there! -Hello!
-我在这里生孩子! -hello
Okay,everyone stand back.
大家退后
Ow.
噢
All right,good thing we're in a hospital.
好吧,好的是我们在医院里
Come on,Lydia,you can do it.
加油,莉迪亚,你办得到
Push him out,push him out. Harder,harder.
用力,用力,使劲,使劲
Push him out,push him out. Way out.
用力,用力,推他出来
Let's get that ball and really move.
我们抢球而且真的动了
Let's get
我们…
I was just Yeah,okay. Push,push,push.
我只是,ok,用力,用力,用力
What are you gonna do, suck the door open?
你想干嘛?将门吸开?
Help! Help!
救命!救命!
And they found their bodies The very next day
第二天,他们终于发现他们的尸体
And they found their bodies The very next
他们终于发现他们的尸体
Mom,everything's going fine.
妈妈,一切顺利
Ross is great.
对,罗斯很好
He's in a whole other place.
他在其他地方
No,he's gone.
不,他不见了
No,you don't have to fly back. Really.
不,你们不用飞回来.真的
What do you mean "This might be your only chance"? I'm only 26.
我唯一的机会?什么意思?我才26岁
I'm not even thinking about babies yet.
我连小孩的事都没想过
-Where have you been? -I just had a baby.
-你上哪儿去了? -我刚生了个小孩
Mazel tov.
了不起
It could be one hour or three.
说不定,或许是一小时也可能是三小时
But relax. She's doing great.
别请放心,她的状况良好
So tell me,are you currently involved with anyone?
告诉我,目前有对象吗?
Not at the moment,I'm not. Are you?
没有,现在没有,你呢?
No,it's hard enough to get women to go out with me.
没有,我不容易找到对象
Right. Yeah,I've heard that about cute doctors.
对,我听过有关帅哥大夫的传间
No,really. I suppose it's because I spend so much time,you know...
没有,真的.我想这是因为我花了太多的时间
...where I do.
在工作上
I try not to let work affect my personal life.
我试着不让工作影响我的生活
But it's hard when,when you do what I do. It's,like....
当你做的时候很难,当我做,像…
Well,for instance, what do you do?
等等,你从事什么工作?
I'm a waitress.
我是服务生
Aren't there times when you come home at night and you're,like:
难道你下班回家后不会觉得…
"If I see one more cup of coffee...."
如果我再看见咖啡杯…
Gotcha.
我懂
-I'm gonna check up on your friend. -That's fine.
-我去看看你朋友. -很好
-How'd you know I was here? -Your mom called me.
-你怎么会知道我在这儿? -你妈打电话告诉我的
So is this her?
这就是她?
No,this is a loaner.
不,这是替代品
Ours is at the shop.
我们的还在商店里
God,I hope she has my brains.
天哪,我希望她有我的头脑
I'm sorry you had to do this by yourself.
抱歉,让你自己承担这一切
I wasn't by myself. I had a doctor, a nurse and a helper guy.
我不是自己一个,我有大夫,护士和善心人士
-So did you see who won the game? -The Knicks by 10. They suck.
-知道谁赢吗? -尼克斯胜十分,他们真烂
They're not so bad.
他们还不算是太烂
Come on. Come on.
拜托,拜托
-You're doing it too hard. -You have to do it hard or else
-你做的太辛苦了. -你应该更努力或者其他什么
Damn it. Damn it.
可恶,可恶
Damn it,damn it. This is all your fault.
可恶…都是你的错
This should be the greatest day of my life.
这本来是我今生最快乐的日子
My son is being born, and I should be in there.
我儿子即将出世,我应该在那儿的
Instead,I'm stuck in a closet with you.
而不是被困在这儿
I have been waiting for this as much as you.
我和你一样期待已久
No one's been waiting for this as much as I have.
不,相信我没人像我如此期待
You know what's funny?
你知道什么最搞笑吗?
You go home with the baby. Where does that leave me?
讽刺的是你们将带着宝宝回家 我剩下什么?
You're his father.
你是他父亲
Who am l? There's Father's Day. There's Mother's Day.
我是谁?这世上有父亲节,母亲节
There's no Lesbian Lover Day.
却没有女同志节
Every day is Lesbian Lover Day.
每天都是女同志节
This is so great.
这真精彩
Do you wanna explain that?
愿意解释吗?
I mean,when I was growing up, my dad left...
因为我小时候我爸离开
...and my mother died and my stepfather went to jail.
我妈过世,我继父入狱
I barely had enough pieces to make one whole parent.
我根本得不到父母的爱
And here's this baby who has three whole parents...
如今他有如此爱他的三个父母
...who fight over who gets to love it the most...
甚至为谁给他的爱最多而吵架
...and it's not even born yet.
而且他根本还未出世
It's just the luckiest baby in the whole world.
他真是全天下最幸福的宝宝
I'm sorry. You were fighting.
抱歉,你们正在吵架
Where are they?
他们在哪儿?
-They'll be here. -They wouldn't miss this.
-他们在哪儿? -他们不会错过的
Relax. You're only at 9 centimeters, and the baby's at zero station.
放轻松.才开九公分,宝宝没那么快出来
You are really frightening me.
你吓到我了
Somebody wanna help me? Trying to rip out my heart.
谁愿意帮我吗?她想掏出我的心脏
That's great. Anybody seen a nipple?
这下可好,有人看见乳头吗?
Ten centimeters. Here we go.
十公分,开始用力
-Time to start pushing. -But they're not here yet.
-开始用力 -他们还没好
-I can't tell the baby to wait. -Oh,God.
-我无法叫宝宝等他们来 -哦,上帝
-Okay,got the vent open. -Hi,I'm Ben.
-通气口开了 -我是本
I'm hospital worker Ben.
我是医院工人本
It's Ben to the rescue.
本前来抢救了
Ben,you ready? Give me your foot.
本,准备好没?脚给我
On three,Ben. One,two,three.
数到三,本.1,2,3
Come on,Ben. That's it,Ben.
来吧,本.就是这样,本
What do you see?
你看见什么?
I see what appears to be a dark vent.
我看见黑暗的通气孔
Wait.
等等
Yes,it is,in fact,a dark vent.
真的是黑暗的通气孔
Pheebs,it's open. It's open.
菲比,门开了
Wait. You forgot your legs.
等等,你们忘了脚
-Push. Push. -We're here. We're here.
-用力,用力 -我们来了,我们来了
Where have you been?
你们上哪儿去了
Long story.
说来话长
I need you to keep pushing. I need Excuse me,can I have this?
卡萝,我要你不断用力 抱歉,我能用这个…
There's too many people here. There's about to be one more.
这里人太多了,而且待会儿又会多一个
So if you're not an ex-husband or lesbian life partner,out you go.
所以不是前任丈夫和女同志终身伴侣者请出去
-Bye-bye. -Good luck,you guys.
-再见了…? -祝你好运.伙计
Do you have to be Carol's lesbian life partner?
我问你,要卡萝的女同志终身伴侣才行吗?
Out.
出去
Here he comes.
他的头露出来了
Let me see. I've gotta see.
让我看看…我看到了
A head.
是头…
It's huge. How are you doing this?
好大,卡萝,你是怎么办到的?
You're not helping.
你真是一点忙都帮不上
You're doing great.
你做得很好…
-Hello? -Oh,sorry.
-你好? -哦,对不起
What do you see? What do you see?
你看见什么?你看见什么?
We got a head. We got arms. Oh,look at the little fingers.
我看到到头,手臂出来了,看看这些小手指
A chest and a stomach...
看,是手指,肚子
...and it's a boy,definitely a boy.
是男的,百分百男孩
Legs,knees and feet.
腿,膝盖和脚
He's here.
他出来了
He's a person.
他是个人
-Look. -What does he look like?
-看. -他看起来像谁?
IKind of like my Uncle Ed, covered in Jell-O.
像我叔叔艾德,被果冻包着
Really?
真的?
You guys,he's beautiful.
各位,他好漂亮
Thanks,Pheebs.
谢了,菲比
No shouting,but we still need a name for this little guy.
不准大吼,我们仍需要为他取个名字
-How about Ben? -I like Ben.
-本如何? -我喜欢本
Ben.
本
Ben's good. How come you never mentioned Ben before?
这名字不错,你们之前怎没提过这名字?
We just cooked it up.
刚想出来的
That's what we were off doing.
这就是我们不在时做的事
-Can we come in? -Yeah,come on.
-我们能进来吗? -当然,请进
I know. I know.
我知道,我知道
Everybody,there's someone I'd like you to meet.
各位,向你们介绍一个人
-This is Ben. -Hi,Ben.
-他叫本. -嗨,本
Ben,this is everybody.
本,这是大家
Susan,he looks just like you.
苏珊,他看起来像你
Thanks.
谢谢
I can't believe one of us actually has one of these.
天啊,没想到我们之中有人生宝宝了
I know. I still am one of these.
我知道,我也是其中之一
Can l?
我能吗?
Okay,the head. You gotta....
好,头,你必须…
I'm your Aunt Monica. Yes,I am.
本,我是你姑姑摩妮卡,没错
I'm your Aunt Monica.
我就是你姑姑摩妮卡
I will always have gum.
我将永远有…牙齿
Ben...
本…
... I want you to know that there may be some times when...
我要你知道有时我会不在
... I may not be around like this.
像这样
But I'll still always come back...
我会回来
...Iike this.
像这样
And sometimes, I may be away longer...
有时我会离开更久
...Iike this.
像这样
But I'll still always come back...
我仍会回来
...Iike this.
像这样
And sometimes,I'll want you to steal third and I'll go like this:
有时我要你到三垒,我会这样
He is so amazing.
他太神奇了
Yeah,I know. Look at him.
对,我知道,你看他
Nothing. I don't think that's his name.
没反应,我想他不喜欢这名字
Look,he's closing his eyes.
看,他闭上眼睛了
Look,he's opening his eyes.
看,他张开眼睛了
He doesn't do much,does he?
他不常动吧?
Nope,this is pretty much it.
这样已算动了
You guys wanna get some coffee?
你们想喝咖啡吗?
I'll see you guys later.
待会儿见
He's closing his eyes again.
看,他又闭上眼睛了